# Clarence E. Stephen

1382 Bedford Ave, Apt 3A, Brooklyn, NY 11216 - clarence.stephen@aya.yale.edu - 315.869.8487

#### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

Data scientist and investment professional with 10 years experience in multi-asset trading, analytic tool development, project management, and data analytics using Python, SQL, VBA, Hadoop, Spark, FactSet, Bloomberg, & CapIQ. Experience in sales across finance, education, and technology sectors. Led equity derivative & FX strategies at Chase Coleman's Tiger Global, generating >\$500m in profits. Led project management for trading related initiatives, automating workflows and leveraging technology to enhance insight and efficiency.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Independent Investments**

2016 - Present

- Private Investments: Since December 2016, 6 companies completed IPOs: Despegar, Netshoes, Redfin, Meitu, Spotify, & Bilibili. Capital initially deployed from 2015 through 2018 including current investments
- 2017: Hedge fund assets +32%, long-only assets +48%, cryptocurrencies +310%
- 2018: Founded an independent online-educational solutions business for freelance and pro bono work

## Tiger Global Management – Multi-Asset Trader

2010 - 2016

- Led equity derivatives strategies exceeding \$350m in profits from 2013 to 2016
- Generated over \$250m in profits and savings on macroeconomic strategies from 2011 to 2016, including foreign bond holdings and FX derivatives; led pricing, execution, hedging, and risk management
- Managed information flow including analysis of news, research, flows, and economic events
- **Project management:** Managed team of 8 developers maintaining trading, compliance, accounting, and operations systems with emphases on automation, error-prevention, compliance, information security, and risk management. Developed portfolio analytics and risk metrics for risk management. Utilized VBA, FactSet, Bloomberg, and CapIQ for data analysis and integration with EZE OMS data feeds.

# Morgan Stanley – Equity Derivatives Analyst • Obtained Series 3, 7, 55, and 63 licenses

2008 - 2010

- Portfolio manager, volatility trader, and market maker for energy, materials, industrial, and utility sectors
- Reduced brokerage and exchange fees by \$5m annually via data analysis and negotiation
- In client-facing sales role, managed 15 accounts to produce \$11m in commissions in 2009; \$14m in 2010
- Programming/financial modeling: Developed volatility metrics leveraging YODA and Rlutils and integrating data into excel with VBA. Models were used for pricing, idea generation, and risk management

## Freudigman & Billings - Tutoring agency - Head of Math & Science Solutions

2004 - 2010, 2017

**Project management:** Founded F&B online-tutoring business and summer boot camp sessions; Piloted development and launch of online tutoring platform, tutortrove.com

## **EDUCATION**

## **Independent Study**

2016 - Present

- Metis Data Science Bootcamp (2018, New York, NY): Full-time, 500hrs+, 12wk intensive training in machine learning, Python, Unix, CSS, JavaScript, D3.js, Hadoop, Spark, data wrangling, project design, data visualization, and communication of results.
- General Assembly SQL Bootcamp: Learning the Language (2018, New York, NY)
- General Assembly Data Science 101: Data mining, machine learning, & python (2018, New York, NY)
- DataCamp.com Intro to Python for Data Science (2018)
- Py.com The Fundamentals Python (2017)

## Yale University, New Haven, CT, B.Sc. in Physics, GPA 3.81, magna cum laude

2004 - 2008

- Sigma Chi Fraternity, Yale Political Union, Yale Rugby
- Richard Light Fellowship Scholar; Japanese-language study abroad; Selected for Directed Studies Program; Quantum computing research lab assistant with Prof. David DeMille

Seminole High, Sanford, FL, IB program, GPA 4.73; Valedictorian (1 of 496), SAT 1570/1600

2000 - 2004

### **SKILLS**

Software/Programming: Python, SQL, C#, VBA (Excel), Unix, JavaScript, CSS, Hadoop, Spark, D3.js, Statistical (MATLAB, LaTeX), Financial (FactSet, Bloomberg, CapIQ)

Languages: Japanese (fluent), Spanish (conversational), French (conversational), Korean (elementary)

Mathematics: American Invitational Mathematics Exam (AIME) 3x qualifier; Mu Alpha Theta national rankings in Geometry 2<sup>nd</sup>, Calculus 43<sup>rd</sup>, Variations & Proportions 3<sup>rd</sup>; over 50 top-rankings at state-level; Coursework includes Multi-variable calculus, linear algebra, calculus of variations, differential equations, statistics & probability